

Prakhar Singh Dhaila

ABOUT ME

Hello! I'm a passionate Software Developer with over four years of experience, specializing in advanced web development. My journey in the tech world has equipped me with a diverse skill-set and a hunger for new challenges. I'm your go-to person for all things JavaScript, and I love working with technologies like ReactJS, Redux, NextJS, and NodeJS. Whether I'm working on solo projects or collaborating in a team, I'm all about getting things done efficiently. I'm also an eager learner, always excited to explore new tech stacks in the ever-expanding world of Software Development.

SKILLS

Technical Skills - ReactJs, Javascript, NextJs, Redux, NodeJs, ExpressJs, MongoDB, MongooseJs, Typescript, Git, HTML, CSS, SCSS, Angular, Figma, Material UI, Jenkins, Bitbucket, JIRA, CI/CD, AWS, Webpack, Web Sockets, Server-Side Events, Terraform, Hasura, GraphQL, Unit Testing, Java, Python, VS Code, Cryptography

Soft Skills - Problem Solving, Critical Thinking, Adaptability, Time Management, Leadership, Ownership, Communication, Attention to detail, Empathy, Ethical Integrity

EXPERIENCE

Freecharge Payment Technologies Private Limited, Gurugram, India — Software Development Engineer

SEP 2021 - AUG 2023

- Collaborated with the core Front-end Development team to create production-ready modules and features for multi-device (responsive) views from scratch.
- Led a team of 3 Developers in building the 'Easy Personal Loan' lending platform for web and mobile (inside a webview).
- Developed the 'Education Fees Via Credit Card' (EFCC) product, generating INR 20 million daily revenue.
- Integrated the Push to VPA feature to 'EFCC' and 'Rent Via CC' products for direct transactions, thereby enhancing the UX.
- Created an Investment platform from scratch with a 4-member team and a reusable Audio/Video recording custom hook for V-KYC using core JavaScript APIs.
- Worked on development of lending platforms like 'Personal Loan +', 'Checkout EMI', and 'PayLater'
- Ensured efficient, modular and reusable code.

- Managed end-to-end feature development in collaboration with cross-functional teams.
- Achieved First Runner-up in a 24-hour Annual Hackathon, winning INR 100,000.
- Provided mentorship to junior developers and actively participated in code reviews.

Compro Technologies, New Delhi, India — Software Engineer

JUL 2019 - SEP 2021

- Worked on a mobile-first, responsive, multi-tenant web application focused on providing e-learning and authoring experiences for teacher/student.
- Developed re-usable theme-driven components with support of internationalization using latest React practices like functional components, hooks (native, custom) and Redux.
- Was responsible for everything in the assigned modules, ranging from designing the low level architecture, implementing code in a modular fashion, deployment, and release.
- Wrote bitbucket pipelines for automation of build deployments to Amazon S3.
- Developed SDKs for authentication from scratch which were used by other teams.
- Used Terraform to automate setting up of the project's AWS cloud infrastructure.
- Involved in implementing the Micro-Frontend approach as part of the core team for our application using the latest Webpack 5 Module Federation.

EDUCATION

University of New Brunswick, Fredericton, NB, Canada — Master of Computer Science by Coursework

SEP 2023 - PRESENT

Presently a Graduate student at UNB, studying subjects like NLP, Cryptanalysis and DB security. Working on practical assignments in Python, Java for creating Machine Learning models and Cryptographic algorithms.

Maharaja Surajmal Institute of Technology, New Delhi, India — B.Tech in CSE

AUG 2015 - JUL 2019

- Graduated with CGPA of 8.22 (82.2%)
- Took part in curricular and extracurricular college events.
- Was part of prestigious college societies like IEEE MSIT, Entrepreneurship-CELL MSIT, Mutants, etc.
- Organized events like LAN Gaming, Face Painting, IPL Auction in our Technical/Cultural Fests.
- Participated in hackathons, for insights into Software Development.

PROJECTS

QA BOT — Team Project, Hackathon

In a 3-developer team, I created an automation tool during a hackathon. The tool enabled individuals without coding experience to generate automation test cases, capture UI screenshots and API request/response snapshots. Built with NextJs, Ant Design, Puppeteer, ResembleJs, Hasura, and GraphQL.

STOIC NOTES — Personal

2021

An easy to use web application with an elegant UI that allows users to create personal notes for their stoic growth - built using MERN stack, Typescript and Webpack.

SHORT URL GENERATOR — Personal

2021

Short URL generator developed on MERN stack, Typescript and Webpack with URL expiration, hit logging, and custom short URL options.

GO CORONA GO — Personal

2021

Created a React app for real-time COVID-19 updates in India, including State and District-level data on active, recovered, and death cases.

HOBBIES

Singing, Reading, Chess, Watching Movies/ TV Series

SOCIAL PROFILES

- LinkedIn: https://www.linkedin.com/in/prakhar-s-dhaila-9384a6165
- Github: https://github.com/pdhaila97
- Personal Portfolio: https://www.prakharsinghdhaila.in